{"questions": [{"question": "Which one is the capital of Morocco?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Casablanca/Marrakech/Fes/Rabat", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "The four main divisions of philosophy are metaphysics, epistomology, axiology and ...", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Aesthetics/Bioethics/Categorical logic/Logic", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which river flows through Egypt?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Nile/Rhine/Amazon/Volga", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the brain of the computer?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Keyboard/Hard drive/CPU/Monitor", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What does RAM stand for?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Read access memory/Random access memory/Run access memory/Random allocation memory", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which was the name of Aphrodite Child's first album?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "666/Reflection/It's Five O'Clock/End Of The World", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What year did Yes release their debut album?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "1973/1974/1969/1971", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which letter is silent in the word 'solemn'?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "n/l/s/m", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "We are at about 4000 BC, looking for the original speakers of Indo-European. What area would be the best place to look?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Northern India/Anatolian plateau/Eurasian steppes/Iberian Peninsula", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of these former languages in Italy is not considered to be an Indo-European language?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "South Picene/Etruscan/Oscan/Umbrian", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of those is not an album by Premiata Forneria Marconi?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Per un amico/Storia di un minuto/Io sono nato libero/L'isola di niente", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "In which modern-day country did the Inca Empire exist?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Guatemala/Peru/Mexico/Venezuela", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which author wrote 'Catch-22' ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Kurt Vonnegut/Joseph Heller/Vladimir Nabokov/Cassandra Clare", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which British band released the album 'Parachutes' ?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Oasis/Pulp/Coldplay/Radiohead", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Tegucigalpa is the capital city of which country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Nicaragua/El Salvador/Honduras/Guatemala", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "When was the partition between India and Pakistan?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "1891/1947/1999/1763", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which English rock band released the song 'Pinball Wizard' ?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Deep Purple/Led Zeppelin/The Who/The Kinks", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "The countries of Belgium, Netherlands, and Luxembourg are together called _______ .", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Benengium/Benelux/Luxelneth/Nethiumberg", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the capital of Chad?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "N'djamena/Bangui/Luanda/Yaounde", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which philosopher famously said 'Man is born free, but is everywhere in chains' ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Baruch de Spinoza/Jean-Paul Sartre/Jean-Jacques Rousseau/Ludwig Wittgenstein", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Who wrote \"The Great Gatsby\" ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Harper Lee/Joseph Heller/Ray Bradbury/F. Scott Fitzgerald", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What did British Honduras change its name to in 1973?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Belize/Guatemala/Barbados/Jamaica", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which US state is divided into two parts by a large lake?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Wisconsin/Michigan/Ohio/Minnesota", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which English heavy metal band released the album 'The Number of the Beast' ?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Judas Priest/Black Sabbath/Mot\u00f6rhead/Iron Maiden", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which is a measure of computer performance in intensive calculations?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "FLOPS/GIGO/POSIX/ECOS", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "When creating a website, what is one of the things, CSS allows you to do?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Copy to clipboard/Database queries/Adjust font size/Attach event listener", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "In which sequence get elements closer to each other as it progresses?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Cauchy sequence/Arithmetic sequence/Fibonacci sequence/Mersenne primes", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the range of this dataset: {7,9,17,6,8}?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "8/6/11/9", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the second note of the major G scale?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "F#/E/C/A", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is a common method for training artificial neural networks?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Hessenberg expansion/Gauss-Jordan elimination/Backpropagation/Vertex enumeration", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which author wrote 'The Lord of the Rings'?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "C. S. Lewis/G. K. Chesterton/J. R. R. Tolkien/Philip Pullman", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which philosopher famously said 'One cannot step twice in the same river' ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Baruch de Spinoza/Ludwig Wittgenstein/Heraclitus/Denis Diderot", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "If a mathematical function is both -injective and surjective-, it is...", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "perijective/superjective/intersubjective/bijective", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "The Occitan language is spoken in certain parts of Southern ... ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "France/Iran/Russia/Mexico", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What transforms high level source code into assembly or machine code?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "decoder/abstracter/embedder/compiler", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the second largest state in the USA?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "California/Oregon/Texas/Florida", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which album cover did Andy Warhol design for the Rolling Stones?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Let it Bleed/Beggars Banquet/Exile on Main St/Sticky Fingers", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of these countries border Russia?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Uzbekistan/Kyrgyzstan/Tajikistan/North Korea", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "A technique in the construction of large language models is RLHF, which stands for Reinforcement Learning from ... ?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Heuristic Factorials/Human Feedback/Hypergeometric Faces/Hidden Frequencies", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Euler's number (e) is the base of ... ?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Complex logarithms/Natural logarithms/Imaginary logarithms/Rational logarithms", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which method can be used to predict the probability of one out of two possible outcomes, based on one or more variables?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Linear regression/Chi-squared test/Logistic regression/Dynamic scaling", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "The language 'Egyptian Arabic' belongs to which language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Afroasiatic/Uralic/Dravidian/Austronesian", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which city is the most populated in South Africa?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Cape Town/Pretoria/Johannesburg/Durban", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2003?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Master and Commander: The Far Side of the World/Mystic River/The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King/Lost in Translation", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which song was originally recorded by Joni Mitchell and was later covered by Crosby, Stills, Nash & Young?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Our House/Carry On/Woodstock/Always Cut My Hair", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Gaborone is the capital city of which country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Lesotho/Malawi/Botswana/Eswatini", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which philosopher famously said 'It is wrong always, everywhere and for everyone, to believe anything upon insufficient evidence' ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "W. K. Clifford/Ludwig Wittgenstein/Friedrich Nietzsche/Aristoteles", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which film contains the character 'Inspector Jacques Clouseau' ?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The Treasure of the Sierra Madre/Apocalypse Now/Fargo/The Pink Panther", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "The language 'Hindi' belongs to which language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Dravidian/Uralic/Indo-European/Austronesian", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "'Finding Nemo' was released in which year?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "1997/2006/2000/2003", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which author wrote 'Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde' ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Robert Louis Stevenson/Oscar Wilde/Joseph Conrad/Agatha Christie", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Who wrote 'The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy' ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Douglas Adams/John Grisham/Terry Pratchett/Stephen King", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "The language 'Hausa' belongs to which language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Afroasiatic/Niger-Congo/Austronesian/Dravidian", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "How are domestic canines more commonly known?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Wolves/Cows/Dogs/Foxes", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Golden Earring had which hit single in 1973?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Radar Love/No For An Answer/Long Blond Animal/Eight Miles High", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "In which year was the Beatles' \"Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band\" released?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "1966/1968/1967/1965", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is phonetics concerned with?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Grammar/Writing/Meaning/Sounds", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Who was considered the 'Father of Linguistics', a Swiss guy, who authored the seminal book entitled 'Course in General Linguistics' ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Ferdinand de Saussure/William James/Noam Chomsky/Leonard Bloomfield", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What animals can breathe \"with their cheeks\" ?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Amphibians/Birds/Mammals/Insects", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Arabic belongs to the ...", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Turkic languages/Nubian languages/Semitic languages/Berber languages", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the derivative of f(x)=sin(x) ?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "cot(x)/cos(x)/tan(x)/-cos(x)", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which is a synonym of 'penitent' ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "diffident/contrite/candent/impolite", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What can be a possible cause for packet loss in the Internet ?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Receive window too large/Phishing attack/Network congestion/Checksum is in binary", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the largest species of shark?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Tiger Shark/Hammerhead Shark/Great White Shark/Whale Shark", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which animal is known for its ability to change color to blend into its surroundings?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Flamingo/Peacock/Chameleon/Octopus", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the primary defense mechanism of a skunk?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Spraying a foul-smelling liquid/Loud screeching/Playing dead/Camouflage", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "How many species of skunks are there?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "4/2/10/12", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What does \"CPU\" stand for in computer terminology?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Central Processing Unit/Central Power Unit/Computer Personal Unit/Control Program Utility", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which programming language is primarily used for web development on the client side?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "C++/Python/Java/JavaScript", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "In computer networking, what does the term \"latency\" refer to?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The maximum bandwidth available in a network/The time it takes for data to travel from the source to the destination/The number of devices connected to a network/The amount of data transmitted over a network", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which significant historical event took place in Augsburg in 1555?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The signing of the Treaty of Augsburg/ The beginning of the Thirty Years' War/The Augsburg Peace of Religion/The establishment of the Augsburg Confession", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the value of the derivative of the function  \ud835\udc53 ( \ud835\udc65 ) = 3 \ud835\udc65 2 \u2212 5 \ud835\udc65 + 4 f(x)=3x  2  \u22125x+4 at the point  \ud835\udc65 = 2 x=2?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "5/10/1/7", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the fundamental theorem of algebra?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Every polynomial can be factored into linear factors./The product of the roots of a polynomial is equal to the constant term./The sum of the angles in a triangle is 180 degrees. /Every polynomial equation of degree n has exactly n roots in the complex number system.", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the profession of the character Sean Maguire, played by Robin Williams, in Good Will Hunting?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Professor/Carpenter/Mathematician/Psychologist", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the primary focus of the film My Own Private Idaho?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "A family's struggle with mental illness./A road trip across America for a music festival./The journey of two friends who are also hustlers./The life of a successful businessman.", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following films is directed by Alejandro Gonz\u00e1lez I\u00f1\u00e1rritu?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "All of the above/Babel/The Revenant/Birdman", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What major event took place in Algeria from 1954 to 1962?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The Battle of Algiers/The establishment of the Algerian Republic/The Algerian War of Independenc/The Algerian Civil War", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What language family does Tigrinya belong to?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Indo-European/Niger-Congo/Sino-Tibetan/Afro-Asiatic", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What was the significance of the Battle of Adwa in 1896 for Ethiopia?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": " It led to the establishment of the Ethiopian Empire./ It was the first time Ethiopia was colonized./It marked the end of the Ethiopian Civil War./It secured Ethiopian sovereignty against Italian invasion.", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What was the title of King Crimson's debut album released in 1969?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Larks' Tongues in Aspic/Discipline/In the Court of the Crimson King/Red", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following novels is considered David Foster Wallace's magnum opus?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The Broom of the System/Infinite Jest/Brief Interviews with Hideous Men/Girl with Curious Hair", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which prestigious award did Elfriede Jelinek receive in 2004?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Nobel Prize in Literature/Goethe Prize/Booker Prize/Pulitzer Prize", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What was the significance of Ravenna during the Roman Empire?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "It served as the main naval base of the Roman fleet./It was the capital of the Western Roman Empire./It was the location of the Colosseum./It was the birthplace of Julius Caesar. ", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following philosophers is most commonly associated with existentialism?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Karl Marx/Immanuel Kant/Jean-Paul Sartre/Friedrich Nietzsche", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is Gottlob Frege primarily known for in the field of philosophy?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Introducing existentialism/Establishing the concept of the unconscious/Founding modern logic and philosophy of language/Developing the theory of relativity", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which concept is most closely associated with Horkheimer and Adorno in their critique of culture and society?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The \"Social Contract\"/Pragmatism/Crisis of Meaning/The \"Culture Industry\"", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the main theme of Rousseau's work The Social Contract?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The necessity of absolute monarchy/The inevitability of social inequality/The importance of individual freedom and the general will/The rejection of private property", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the primary diet of raccoons (Procyon lotor)?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Herbivorous, primarily feeding on plants/Omnivorous, eating both plant and animal matter/Insectivorous, primarily feeding on insects/Carnivorous, primarily feeding on other animals", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is a unique reproductive feature of seahorses (Hippocampus)?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "They reproduce asexually. /They have a symbiotic relationship with other fish for reproduction./The males carry and incubate the eggs in a pouch./They lay eggs in a nest.", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is one of the most distinctive social behaviors of bonobos (Pan paniscus)?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "They exhibit strong male dominance hierarchies./They primarily use tools for foraging. /They use sexual behavior to resolve conflicts and strengthen social bonds./They are strictly solitary animals.", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What major event occurred in the Democratic Republic of the Congo in 1960?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The Congo Crisis and the declaration of independence from Belgium/The establishment of Belgian colonial rule/The rise of Mobutu Sese Seko to power/The first democratic elections", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following works is written by Dimitri Verhulst?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "The Discovery of Heaven/The Misfortunates/The Sorrow of Belgium/The Book of Chameleons", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the primary reason for the hibernation of dormice (Gliridae), commonly known as \"Siebenschl\u00e4fer\"?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "To avoid predators/To enter a mating period/To survive food scarcity during winter/To migrate to warmer climates", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following mechanisms do Venus flytraps (Dionaea muscipula) use to capture their prey?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Adhesive trapping/Passive trapping/Pitfall trapping/Snap trapping", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which novel is J.D. Salinger best known for, featuring the character Holden Caulfield?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Raise High the Roof Beam, Carpenter/Franny and Zooey/Nine Stories/The Catcher in the Rye", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the scientific name for the giant sequoia, commonly known as the mammoth tree?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Sequoiadendron giganteum/Metasequoia glyptostroboides/Sequoia sempervirens/Taxodium distichum", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following novels was written by Clemens J. Setz?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "The Hour of the Star/The Invention of Morel/Indigo/The Floating Theatre", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the primary purpose of eigenvalues and eigenvectors in linear algebra?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "To analyze linear transformations and their effects on vector spaces/To calculate the determinant of a matrix/To determine the rank of a matrix/To solve systems of equations", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following distributions is characterized by its bell-shaped curve and is commonly used in statistics?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Binomial distribution/Poisson distribution/Normal distribution/Exponential distribution", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following novels is written by Tahar Ben Jelloun?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "The Name of the Rose/This Blinding Absence of Light/The Invisible Man/The Sand Child", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following authors is known for their significant contributions to Maghrebian literature?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Mario Vargas Llosa/Naguib Mahfouz/Assia Djebar/Gabriel Garc\u00eda M\u00e1rquez", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "When was Heidelberg University founded?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "1386/1600/1453/1750", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Who wrote the famous poem \"Heidelberg\" and visited the city several times in the 19th century?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Friedrich Schiller/Mark Twain/Heinrich Heine/Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In which movie did Matt Damon portray an astronaut stranded on Mars?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Interstellar/Gravity/Elysium/The Martian", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the name of the famous street depicted in Fellini's La Dolce Vita?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Via Appia/Via Condotti/Via del Corso/Via Veneto", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following films is a political satire directed by Nanni Moretti?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Mia Madre/Caro Diario/Il Caimano/La Messa \u00e8 Finita", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Zabriskie Point is famous for its final sequence. What happens during this scene?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "A car chase through the desert/A house explodes in slow motion/The protagonists escape to Mexico/A protest turns violent", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the main theme of Ken Park?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Political activism and rebellion/Teenage alienation and dysfunctional families/Urban crime and corruption/Drug addiction and recovery", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which character is an undercover cop infiltrating the Irish mob in The Departed?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Frank Costello/Sean Dignam/Colin Sullivan/Billy Costigan", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the meaning of the standard deviation in a dataset?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The average of the data points/The measure of the spread or dispersion of the data/The square of the mean/The range of the dataset", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the determinant of a square matrix used to determine?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The eigenvalues of the matrix/The rank of the matrix/The trace of the matrix/Whether the matrix is invertible", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the main focus of Wittgenstein's early work, Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Ethics and morality/Language and its relation to reality/The nature of time/The existence of God", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the primary concern of linguistic philosophy?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The classification of languages/The study of phonetics and grammar/The relationship between language, thought, and reality/The history of language development", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is Giambattista Vico's view on the nature of human history?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "History is cyclical and characterized by recurring themes and patterns/History is solely determined by economic factors/History is linear and progresses towards a specific goal/History is completely random and lacks any discernible order", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which philosopher proposed the idea that history is a struggle between the ruling class and the oppressed class?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Karl Marx/Max Weber/Alexis de Tocqueville/Michel Foucault", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What significant event occurred in 711 AD that impacted the history of Andalusia?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The discovery of America/The Reconquista/The establishment of the Spanish Inquisition/The arrival of the Moors and the beginning of Muslim rule", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which event in 1979 dramatically changed the political landscape of Iran?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The Anglo-Persian War/The Iran-Iraq War/The Constitutional Revolution/The Islamic Revolution", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What was the Aksum Empire primarily known for?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Its naval power and exploration/Its vast collection of written literature/Its conquests of neighboring territories/Its advanced agricultural techniques and trade networks", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following empires is associated with the rise of Timbuktu as a prominent city?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The Byzantine Empire/The Ottoman Empire/The Roman Empire/The Mali Empire", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Timbuktu is located in which present-day country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Burkina Faso/Senegal/Nigeria/Mali", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What was the capital of the Byzantine Empire?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Constantinople/Athens/Alexandria/Rome", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is a neural network?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "A hardware component of a computer/A type of computer virus/A network of interconnected computers/A computational model inspired by the way biological neural networks in the human brain process information", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which novel is based on Thomas Mann's own family background and examines the decline of a wealthy merchant family?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The Holy Sinner/The Magic Mountain/Confessions of Felix Krull/Buddenbrooks", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "In which city was Goethe born?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Berlin/Stuttgart/Weimar/Frankfurt am Main", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Sloths are known for their slow metabolism. Approximately how long can it take for a sloth to digest food?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "30-40 hours/2-3 hours/1-2 weeks/12-24 hours", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What family do dogs, wolves, and foxes belong to?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Mustelidae/Ursidae/Felidae/Canidae", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Domestic pigs are known for their intelligence. Which of the following animals are they often compared to in terms of cognitive abilities?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Dogs/Cats/Cows/Horses", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What does \"open\" software mean?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Software that is only available online/Software that requires a license/Software whose source code is available for modification and distribution/Software that is free of charge", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which sorting algorithm is known for its efficiency in large datasets and is commonly implemented in many programming languages?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Quick Sort/Insertion Sort/Selection Sort/Bubble Sort", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following is a fundamental data structure in computer science used to store a collection of items?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Tree/All of the above/Graph/Array", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which philosophical tradition is Hegel associated with?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Rationalism/Empiricism/Idealism/Existentialism", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the title of Spinoza's most significant work, where he presents his philosophical ideas on God, nature, and ethics?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Tractatus Politicus/Ethics/Theological-Political Treatise/Axioms of Religion", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Meister Eckhart was a prominent figure in which philosophical and theological tradition?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Sufism/Christian Mysticism/Scholasticism/Rationalism", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the definition of a limit in the context of calculus?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The area under a curve./The rate of change of a function. /The highest value of a function./The value that a function approaches as the input approaches a certain point.", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of a normal distribution?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "It is skewed to the right./It is uniform./It has a mean, median, and mode that are all equal./It has two peaks.", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "In calculus, what does the derivative of a function represent?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The instantaneous rate of change of the function./The maximum value of the function./The average rate of change of the function./The area under the curve of the function.", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following is one of Camille Saint-Sa\u00ebns's most famous works?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The Nutcracker Suite/The Rite of Spring/The Four Seasons/Carnival of the Animals", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which instrument did John Coltrane play?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Trumpet/Piano/Saxophone/Trombone", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Holst composed \"The Planets\" between 1914 and 1917. How many movements are in this suite?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "9/5/7/8", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "In which film did Woody Allen win an Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Match Point/Hannah and Her Sisters/Crimes and Misdemeanors/Annie Hall", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following films is directed by Pedro Almod\u00f3var?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Pan's Labyrinth/Am\u00e9lie/Talk to Her/The Sea Inside", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following films directed by Herzog features a narrative about the construction of an opera house in the Amazon rainforest?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Nosferatu/My Best Fiend/Fitzcarraldo/Stroszek", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Thomas Bernhard often criticized which aspect of Austrian culture in his writings?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The education system/The arts/Environmental issues/Nationalism and conformity", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the title of Hemingway's novella that tells the story of an old fisherman and his struggle with a giant marlin?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The Old Man and the Sea/Islands in the Stream/The Snows of Kilimanjaro/A Moveable Feast", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the study of the rules governing the structure of sentences in a language called?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Morphology/Syntax/Pragmatics/Semantics", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In phonetics, what is the term for the smallest unit of sound that can distinguish meaning in a language?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Allophone/Morpheme/Phoneme/Grapheme", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which theory posits that the structure of a language influences its speakers' worldview or cognition?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Generative Grammar/Structuralism/Universal Grammar/Relativity Hypothesis (Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis)", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the approximate length of the Niger River, making it one of the longest rivers in Africa?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "4200 kilometers/5800 kilometers/2600 kilometers/1600 kilometers", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "The Danube Delta, a UNESCO World Heritage site, is located in which country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Serbia/Romania/Bulgaria/Hungary", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following countries shares a border with Niger?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Mali/Nigeria/All of the above/Algeria", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which city, known as a center of learning and trade, was part of the Mali Empire?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Lagos/Cairo/Timbuktu/Marrakech", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What was the primary military tactic used by the Mongol armies that contributed to their success?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Siege warfare/Fast cavalry and mobility/Naval warfare/Guerrilla warfare", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following cat breeds is known for being hairless?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Persian/Sphynx/Siamese/Maine Coon", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of these North American animals is known for its role in shaping river ecosystems by building dams?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Grizzly Bear/Gray Wolf/American Bison/North American Beaver", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "In the context of database management, what does the acronym ACID stand for?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Durability/Availability, Concurrency, Integrity, Deletion/Asynchronous, Centralized, Inverse, Denormalized/Authorization, Compression, Inference, Distribution", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which algorithmic paradigm does the Dijkstra's algorithm for shortest paths primarily rely on?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Divide and Conquer/Dynamic Programming/Backtracking/Greedy Algorithm", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which is the longest mountain range in Africa?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Drakensberg Mountains/Rwenzori Mountains/Atlas Mountains/Simien Mountains", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the world highest mountain?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Denali/K2/Kilimanjaro/Mount Everest", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which empire was known for its extensive trade networks and cultural exchanges during the early modern period in India?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Mughal Empire/Gupta Empire/Chola Dynasty/Maurya Empire", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which civilization is known for its advanced architectural achievements and the creation of the calendar, and was prominent in Mexico before the Spanish conquest?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Aztec/Inca/Olmec/Maya", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following language families includes languages such as Russian, Polish, and Czech?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Romance/Slavic/Semitic/Germanic", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the primary characteristic that defines a language as belonging to the Sino-Tibetan language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "It uses an alphabetic writing system./It has no grammatical structure./It is tonal and primarily spoken in East Asia./ It includes only languages spoken in China.", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which theorem states that every continuous function on a closed interval attains its maximum and minimum values?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Extreme Value Theorem/Intermediate Value Theorem/Bolzano-Weierstrass Theorem/Mean Value Theorem", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which theorem provides a method for approximating the value of a function using its derivatives at a single point?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Fundamental Theorem of Calculus/L'H\u00f4pital's Rule/Pythagorean Theorem/Taylor's Theorem", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the central theme of Pedro Almod\u00f3var's film \"Todo sobre mi madre\" (All About My Mother)?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The complexities of motherhood and identity/The search of a lost child/The challenges of aging/The impact of war on families", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which Alfred Hitchcock film features a character named Marion Crane, who becomes the victim of a notorious shower scene?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "North By Northwest/Rear Window/Vertigo/Psycho", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is a primary characteristic that distinguishes heavy metal music from hard rock?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Inclusion of acoustic instruments/Heavier guitar riffs and darker themes/Use of clean vocals/Emphasis on melodic hooks", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which Focus album, released in 1971, features the hit single \"Hocus Pocus\"?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Focus III/Moving Waves/Live at the Rainbow/Hamburger Concerto", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which philosopher is known for the statement \"I think, therefore I am\"?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "John Locke/Ren\u00e9 Descartes/Friedrich Nietzsche/Immanuel Kant", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Schelling primarily associated with, emphasizing the idea of nature as a dynamic and self-revealing process?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Absolute Idealism/Dialectical Materialism/Transcendental Idealism/Philosophy of Nature", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What scientific suborder does the family Hyaenidae belong to ?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Feliformia/Caniformia/Ciconiiformes/Haplorhini", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the scientific name of the cheetah?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Acinonyx jubatus/Felis catus/Panthera onca/Lynx rufus", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What bird is born with claws on its wing digits?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Hoatzin/Secretary bird/Cassowary/Cormorant", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of these is not a layer in the OSI model for data communications?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Application Layer/Physical Layer/Connection Layer/Transport Layer", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What port does HTTP run on?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "23/53/80/443", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What does the International System of Quantities refer 1024 bytes as?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Kelobyte/Kibibyte/Kylobyte/Kilobyte", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of these is NOT a real tectonic plate?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Eurasian Plate/North American Plate/Atlantic Plate/Nazca Plate", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the most populous Muslim-majority nation in 2010?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Iran/Saudi Arabia/Indonesia/Sudan", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "How many countries border Kyrgyzstan?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "4/6/1/3", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "The Second Boer War in 1899 was fought where?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "South Africa/Nepal/Argentina/Bulgaria", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which day did World War I begin?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "April 28/June 28/January 28/July 28", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "How many women joined the United States Armed Services during World War II?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "350000/250000/100000/500000", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the approximate value of mathematical constant e?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "3.14/1.41/1.62/2.72", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the smallest number that can be expressed as the sum of two positive cubes in two different ways?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "4104/91/1729/561", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "The decimal number 31 in hexadecimal would be what?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "2E/3D/1F/1B", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "In which African country was the 2006 film 'Blood Diamond' mostly set in?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Sierra Leone/Liberia/Central African Republic/Burkina Faso", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What was the first feature-length computer-animated movie?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Tron/Lion king/101 Dalmatians/Toy Story", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Who directed \"E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial\" (1982)?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Tim Burton/Stanley Kubrick/James Cameron/Steven Spielberg", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Who was the guitarist in the band \"The Doors\"?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Robby Krieger/Jim Morrison/Ray Manzarek/John Densmore", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What was the name of Pink Floyd's first studio album?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Ummagumma/Atom Heart Mother/More/The Piper at the Gates of Dawn", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What was The Velvet Underground's first album called?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Loaded/White Light-White Heat/The Velvet Underground/The Velvet Underground & Nico", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which author co-wrote \"The Communist Manifesto\" alongside Karl Marx?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Gottlob Frege/Arthur Schopenhauer/Friedrich Engels/Ludwig Wittgenstein", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "The novel \"Of Mice And Men\" was written by what author?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "John Steinbeck/Mark Twain/Harper Lee/George Orwell", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "In the year 1818, novelist Mary Shelly is credited with writing a fiction novel and creating this infamous character.", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The Invisible Man/Dracula/Frankenstein's monster/The Thing", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Who wrote the novel \"Moby Dick\"?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "William Golding/J. R. R. Tolkien/William Shakespeare/Herman Melville", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which concept is central to Schopenhauer's philosophy and is described as the driving force behind all life and phenomena?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Will/Being/Reason/Knowledge", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "In Thus Spoke Zarathustra, what concept does Nietzsche introduce as a model for personal growth, symbolizing an ideal of strength, creativity, and self-overcoming?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Slave Morality/\u00dcbermensch (Overman)/Apollonian and Dionysian/Eternal Recurrence", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of these languages does not use articles?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Swahili/Italian/Turkish/Arabic", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the term for a speech sound produced without any significant constriction of the airflow in the vocal tract?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Fricative/Affricate/Plosive/Vowel", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "In phonetics, which of the following describes a sound made by fully stopping the airflow and then releasing it, as in the sounds /p/ or /t/?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Lateral/Plosive/Approximant/Nasal", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the average age at which women enter menopause?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "~46 years/~64 years/~39 years/~51 years", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "\"hitherto\" means ... ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "up until now/in due course/thereupon/before long", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which word contains a velar consonant?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "bee/gay/they/lie", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "How many bones does a white shark have in its body?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "56/333/216/0", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What philosopher wrote \"Leviathan\" ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Bertrand Russell/John Stuart Mill/Thomas Hobbes/Karl Popper", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Deep neural networks are so called, because they have multiple ... ?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Hidden layers/Decision trees/Markov chains/Clustered indices", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which fish spawns in freshwater, but spends its adult life at sea?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Salmon/Swordfish/Tuna/American eel", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which country occupied Albania from 1939 to 1943?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Spain/Yugoslavia/Italy/Romania", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of these pairs of words are antonyms?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "congenial-vitrolic/antiquated-archaic/destitute-bankrupt/belligerent-pugnacious", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which is an alternative to gradient descent when constructing artificial neural networks?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Huffman coding/Marzullo synchronisation/Exponential backoff/Neuroevolution", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which network encrypts and passes on data through random relays to ensure Internet anonymity?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Tor/Mig/Fub/Jag", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of these philosophers lived in the 20th century?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Gottfried Leibniz/Karl Popper/Ren\u00e9 Descartes/Arthur Schopenhauer", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following characteristics is unique to the traditional playing style of the Appalachian dulcimer compared to other stringed instruments?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "It has frets that allow microtonal tuning./It is typically held and played flat on the lap./It is played with a bow rather than plucked./It uses double-course strings exclusively", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following bands was a key figure in the \"British Invasion,\" bringing British rock and pop music to the United States in the 1960s?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The Rolling Stones/The Byrds/Creedence Clearwater Revival/The Beach Boys", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which music genre is Creedence Clearwater Revival most commonly associated with, blending rock and roll with Southern, blues, and country influences?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Swamp Rock/Psychedelic Rock/Southern Rock/Folk Rock", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following novels by John Irving tells the story of a writer reflecting on his life, love, and the influence of wrestling?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The Cider House Rules/Last Night in Twisted River/The World According to Garp/A Prayer for Owen Meany", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "In which film series did Tobey Maguire gain widespread fame for portraying a character with superhuman abilities and a strong sense of responsibility?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Spider-Man/X-Men/The Lord of the Rings/The Matrix", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "In which critically acclaimed film did River Phoenix portray a group of boys who go on a journey to find their missing friend, ultimately confronting issues of friendship and loss?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The River Wild/The Thing Called Love/Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade/Stand By Me", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "In Into the Wild, which real-life figure does Emile Hirsch portray, who abandons his possessions and embarks on a journey across America to live in the Alaskan wilderness?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Christopher McCandless/Jack Kerouac/Henry David Thoreau/John Muir", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which novel by Jack Kerouac is considered a defining work of the Beat Generation, chronicling a series of spontaneous road trips across the United States?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The Dharma Bums/Big Sur/On the Road/Visions of Cody", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which philosophical theme is central to Thoreau's Walden, emphasizing self-reliance and individualism in the face of societal pressures?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Romanticism/Naturalism/Transcendentalism/Realism", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which novel by William Burroughs is considered a landmark work of the Beat Generation, known for its experimental narrative style and themes of addiction and control?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Junk/Naked Lunch/On the Road/Soft Machine", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following bands is most closely associated with the Canterbury Scene, known for its blend of progressive rock and jazz influences?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Genesis/Soft Machine/King Crimson/Yes", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which band is considered the pioneer of the Zeuhl genre, known for its blend of progressive rock, jazz, and a unique rhythmic style, often characterized by repetitive basslines and choral vocals?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Heldon/Magma/Univers Zero/Gong", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In Frank Zappa's 1970 album Burnt Weeny Sandwich, which track is notable for its jazz influences and features a prominent guitar solo by Zappa?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Bobby Brown/The Gumbo Variations/The Little House I Used to Live In/Peaches en Regalia\"", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which Free song, released in 1970, became one of the band's most famous tracks and is known for its powerful vocals by Paul Rodgers and its iconic guitar riff?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "All Right Now/Wishing Well/Fire and Water/Heavy Load", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which Zucchero song, released in 1987, features a blend of blues and rock influences and is one of his most successful hits, often performed in both Italian and English?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Il Volo/Diamante\"/Baila (Sexy Thing)/Senza una Donna", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which Talking Heads song, released in 1980 and featured on the album Remain in Light, is known for its Afrobeat-inspired rhythms and became one of the band's signature tracks?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Life During Wartime/Burning Down the House/Once in a Lifetime/Psycho Killer", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which piece by Claude Debussy, inspired by a poem by St\u00e9phane Mallarm\u00e9, is considered a turning point in modern music for its use of impressionistic harmonies and orchestration?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Images/Clair de Lune/Pr\u00e9lude \u00e0 l'apr\u00e8s-midi d'un faune/La Mer", "correctOption": 2}]}
